AKASH JHA

Python Developer

9380638518 @ akash94.jha16@gmail.com

Chennai

SUMMARY

Eager Python developer with 4 years exploiting model-template-view architectural pattern of Django and flask framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs. Specializes in creating accessible, data-driven web assets. Keen to apply expansive development knowledge to deliver fast, efficient client projects and In-House products.

EXPERIENCE

Python Developer

2021 - Ongoing

Fleet Studio Technologies Pvt Ltd

Chennai

Wally (Tool to make website WCAG Compliant): -

- Worked on building a Wally product a web accessibility software referring WCAG compliance.
- Wally provide an inclusive experience for the widest possible range of visitors including those who are living with visual, physical or sensory impairments.
- Tech Stack AWS Lambda, EC2, S3, Python, Flask Framework, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ

Shopify Extension Plugin: -

- * Created a plugin in the Shopify Marketplace so it can be installed in the Shop merchantand merchant can create rules as per the points so on the basis of customers purchase and amount they have spent they will earn points and earned points can be used to getthe discount coupons.
- * Tech Stack Flask, MYSQL, SQLAlchemy, Python

HashOff (Influencer Marketing Product): -

- Involved in building APIs for the Client Project and In-House product development with Flask as web framework
- * Fetched the data from the Social Medias like YouTube, Twitter, TikTok etc
- Tech Stack AWS EC2, Elasticsearch, Python, Flask Framework, MySQL, SQL Alchemy (ORM).

Software Engineer

04/2019 - 02/2021

MasterCom Technology Services India Pvt. Ltd

Bengaluru

- Involved in building database model views utilizing Python, in order to build aninteractive web based solution
- * Used Django as a Web Framework and developed Web Applications

Deployment Engineer

04/2017 - 06/2018

Wipro Limited

Bengaluru

Worked with HOLMES team to deploy the created applications

Apprentice Trainee

08/2016 - 04/2017

Defense Research and Development Organization, GTRE

Bengaluru

* Worked with Sc. F on Frama-C tool to check RTEs of Kaveri Jet Engine.

EDUCATION

B.E. Information Technology

D.Y. Patil College of Engineering

05/2012 - 06/2016

SKILLS

Python

Django

AWS Lambda

ELASTICSEARCH

Flask

AWS S3